sustainlane.com 2010-08-26

# Privacy Policy - Sustainlane

## SustainLane.com and SustainableCircles.com

**Privacy Policy**

(Updated On August 28, 2008)

**PLEASE READ THIS PRIVACY POLICY CAREFULLY BEFORE USING THIS SITE.**

SustainableCircles Corp. (" **SustainableCircles** ," " **we** ," " **us** ", " **our** ") provides various websites such as [www.sustainablecircles.com](http://www.re-mission.net/), [www.sustainlane.com](http://www.sustainlane.com/) , [www.sustainlane.tv](http://www.sustainlane.tv/), [www.sustainlane.us](http://www.sustainlane.us/), [www.sustainlane.net](http://www.sustainlane.net/), [www.theunsustainables.com](http://www.theunsustainables.com/), [www.sustainlanegreenadnetwork.com](http://www.sustainlanegreenadnetwork.com/), [www.unsustainables.com](http://www.unsustainables.com/) and other websites to which this Privacy Policy is linked (collectively, the " **Site(s)** "). Your privacy is very important to us and we are committed to protecting the privacy of our users (" **users** ," " **you** " or " **your** "). Although SustainableCircles respects your privacy, we do collect information from you. This Privacy Policy along with our Terms of Use ([www.sustainlane.com/sp/help/terms-use.jsp](http://www.sustainlane.com/sp/help/terms-use.jsp)) govern your interaction with our Sites, and your registration for and use of our Sites. Except as set forth within this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Use and other published guidelines, we do not release personally identifiable information about our users without their permission.

**1.** ******Introduction**

While you may use some of the functionality of our Sites without registration, some of the specific tools and services might require registration. If you do not register with or use the tools, features or services offered on or through our Sites, the only information we collect will be "Non-Personal Information" (i.e., Information that is not traceable back to you and cannot be used to identify you. Non-Personal Information includes information such as the web pages that you have viewed.) through the use of Cookies (i.e., Small data files that are stored on the hard drive of a computer used to view web sites that are accessible only by the party or site that placed the Cookie on the hard drive.). If registration is required and you choose to register through our Sites, we will require you to submit "Personally Identifiable Information" (i.e., Information that can be traced back to you. Personally Identifiable Information includes information such as your name, home address, telephone number and email address). You are responsible for ensuring the accuracy of the Personally Identifiable Information you submit to SustainableCircles. Inaccurate information will affect the information you receive when using our Sites and tools and our ability to contact you. For example, your email address should be kept current because that is one of the primary manners in which we communicate with you.

**2.** ******Consent**

BY SUBMITTING PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION TO US, AND/OR BY USING THE SITE, YOU AGREE THAT WE MAY COLLECT, USE AND DISCLOSE SUCH PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION IN ACCORDANCE WITH THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND TERMS OF USE, AND AS PERMITTED OR REQUIRED BY LAW.

If you do not agree with these terms, do not provide any Personally Identifiable Information to us. If you refuse or withdraw your consent, or if you choose not to provide us with any required Personally Identifiable Information, we may not be able to provide you with products or services that can be offered on our Sites only if we have access to certain Personally Identifiable Information.

**3.** ******The Information We Gather**

SustainableCircles gathers two types of information about users:

**3.1.** ******Non-Personal Information.** When users come to our Sites, we collect and aggregate Non-Personal Information indicating, among other things, which pages of the Site were visited, the order in which they were visited and which hyperlinks were "clicked." Collecting such information involves the logging of the IP addresses, operating system and browser software used by each user to our Sites. Although such information is not Personally Identifiable Information, we can determine from an IP address a users Internet Service Provider and the geographic location of his or her point of connectivity.

We also use Cookies to help us determine the type of content and sites to which a user to our Site links, the length of time each user spends at any particular area of the Site and the specific functionality that users choose to use. Essentially, Cookies are a users identification card for the SustainableCircles servers. Cookies are only read by the server that placed them, and are unable to execute any code or virus. Cookies allow SustainableCircles to serve you better and more efficiently, and to personalize your experience at our Sites. Cookies also may be used to facilitate a users log-in, but are not used to retain Personally Identifiable Information.

You should be able to control how and whether Cookies will be accepted by your web browser. Most browsers offer instructions on how to reset the browser to reject Cookies in the "Help" section of the toolbar. If you reject our Cookies, certain of the functions and conveniences of our Sites may not work properly, but you do not have to accept our Cookies in order to productively use our Sites.

**3.2.** ******Personally Identifiable Information.** We collect Personally Identifiable Information that you provide to us when you register with us, respond to a poll or questionnaire, sign-up for newsletters and email messages, send us email messages and participate in the following features of our Sites: message boards; blogs; polls and other forums. Among other things, we may use the Personally Identifiable Information that you provide to respond to your questions, provide you the specific services you select, send you the products that you order, send you newsletters about topics chosen by you, send you email messages about Site maintenance and updates, and inform you of significant changes to this Privacy Policy.

**(a)** ******Registration.** In order to use many of the features and functionality of our Sites, we will require you to register with us. During the registration process, you will need to provide us with Personally Identifiable Information that may include, but may not be limited to, your name, age, gender, mailing address, email address, phone number, facsimile number, employer, employment responsibilities and personal interests. SustainableCircles will rely on you to self-report accurate information, and will not take steps to verify any information that you provide.

**(b)** ******Polls.** In connection with the research that SustainableCircles conducts and to educate others about living a healthy, more sustainable life, our users may be asked to voluntarily answer polls and/or questionnaires (" **Polls** ") that may require the users to provide Personally Identifiable Information to SustainableCircles.

**(c)** ******Forums.** SustainableCircles may offer various forums (collectively, the " **Forums** ") at our Sites that may include, but are not limited to: message boards; blogs; and other forums. Depending on the type of Forum, you may be able to submit the following types of information and materials to SustainableCircles: articles and other information.

**(d)** ******Newsletters and Email to You.** During registration and when you access your account information through our Sites, you will be given the option of receiving recurring informational newsletters via email from SustainableCircles. In order to subscribe to such newsletters via email, we need your contact information, such as name and email address. At the time you sign up for our email newsletters or any time thereafter, you can choose to opt-out of receiving additional newsletters from SustainableCircles by sending an email message to [kOspntlOludts](http://www.sustainlane.com/#) and stating in the body of the email message the name of the newsletter(s) that you no longer want to receive. You also can unsubscribe from a particular newsletter by simply clicking on the "unsubscribe" link at the bottom of any such email newsletter. An email to our automated unsubscribe service will be created on your computer. Click the "send" button. You will then be unsubscribed from that newsletter within two to three business days.

**(e)** ******Purchases.** When purchasing products or services through our Sites, users are required to provide SustainableCircles with Personally Identifiable Information. SustainableCircles uses this Personally Identifiable Information to process the order, send the product and/or provide the service.

**(f)** ******Participation In Contests, Sweepstakes and Other Promotions.** From time to time, SustainableCircles may offer you the opportunity to participate in a contest, sweepstakes or other promotion through our Sites. If you desire to participate in any such contest, sweepstakes or other promotion, you will be asked to provide us with certain information necessary to conduct such contest, sweepstakes or other promotion. This information may include, among other things, your name, age, mailing address, email address and phone number.

**(g)** ******Communications with SustainableCircles.** SustainableCircles may receive Personally Identifiable Information when you send an email message to or otherwise contact SustainableCircles.

**4.** ******How We Use (and Do Not Use) the Information We Gather**

Please take some time to familiarize yourself with the different ways SustainableCircles uses the information that we gather.

**4.1.** ******Non-Personal Information.** SustainableCircles uses Non-Personal Information in aggregate form to build higher quality, more useful services by performing statistical analyses of the collective characteristics and behavior of our users, and by measuring demographics and interests regarding specific areas of our Sites.

**4.2.** ******Personally Identifiable Information.** This Privacy Policy serves as notice that SustainableCircles collects Personally Identifiable Information in the manners described herein. Except as set forth in this Privacy Policy or as specifically agreed to by you, SustainableCircles will not disclose any Personally Identifiable Information we gather from you on our Sites. SustainableCircles will release Personally Identifiable Information to third parties: (a) to comply with valid legal requirements such as a law, regulation, search warrant, subpoena or court order; or (b) in special cases, such as a physical threat to you or others. In the event that we are legally compelled to disclose your Personally Identifiable Information to a third party, we will attempt to notify you unless doing so would violate the law or court order. We cooperate with law enforcement agencies in identifying those who may be using our servers or services for illegal activities. We also reserve the right to report any suspected illegal activity to law enforcement individuals or entities for investigation or prosecution. In addition to the other uses set forth in this Privacy Policy, we may disclose and otherwise use Personally Identifiable Information as described below.

**(a)** ******Registration.** SustainableCircles may use the Personally Identifiable Information that we collect from you during registration to contact you in connection with your use of our Sites and to track who uses the various features and functionality offered at our Sites. Additionally, we may use this information in determining the types of features, functionality, products and services to offer through our Sites or otherwise.

**(b)** ******Polls.** SustainableCircles may analyze and use the information received from and the responses to the Polls in connection with the research conducted by or on behalf of SustainableCircles and/or its partners and/or sponsors. Additionally, SustainableCircles may publish on our Sites and/or in other publications the information received from and the responses to the Polls. Although SustainableCircles may publish the information received from and the responses to the Polls, SustainableCircles will not publish any information that identifies any individual user.

**(c)** ******Forums.** SustainableCircles may analyze and use the information received from your use of the Forums in connection with the research conducted by or on behalf of SustainableCircles and/or its partners and/or sponsors. Additionally, SustainableCircles may publish the information received from your use of the Forums either on our Sites and/or in other publications.

**(d)** ******Newsletters and Email to You.** SustainableCircles uses contact information collected during registration to send you the newsletters and email messages that you request us to send you.

**(e)** ******Purchases.** SustainableCircles uses this Personally Identifiable Information collected during the purchasing process to fulfill the order, send the product and/or provide the service.

**(f)** ******Participation In Contests, Sweepstakes and Other Promotions.   **SustainableCircles uses the Personally Identifiable Information that we collect from you when you a contest, sweepstakes or other promotion through our Sites for processing purposes. If a third party administers the contest, sweepstakes or other promotion, your participation may be subject to that third party's terms and conditions, and privacy policy. Detailed information about these terms will be provided on the applicable form you will be asked to fill out.

**(g)** ******Communications with SustainableCircles.** When you send an email message to or other wise contact SustainableCircles, SustainableCircles may use the information provided by you to respond to your communication and/or as described in this Privacy Policy. Also, SustainableCircles may archive this information.

**(h)** ******Disclosure to SustainableCircles Operations and Maintenance Contractors.** SustainableCircles operations and maintenance contractors sometimes have limited access to your Personally Identifiable Information in the course of providing products or services to SustainableCircles. These contractors include vendors and suppliers that provide us with technology, services, and/or content related to better operation and maintenance of our Sites. Unless you have opted-out of receiving emails and newsletters from SustainableCircles, these contractors also may have access to your email address to send newsletters to you on our behalf. Access to your Personally Identifiable Information by these contractors is limited to the information reasonably necessary for the contractor to perform its limited function for SustainableCircles. We also contractually require that our operations and maintenance contractors not use or disclose your Personally Identifiable Information for any purpose other than providing us with products and services.

**5.   Third Party Service Providers **

We use third-party advertising companies and advertising networks to collect information and serve ads to you when you visit our site. These companies may use cookies, pixel tags, web beacons or otherwise independently collect information from or about you and use this information about your visits to this and other sites to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. We do not control their collection and use of information. 

We also operate the SustainLane Green Ad Network, a service that delivers advertisements from participating advertisers to participating publishers. We use third parties to assist with various functions and features of the SustainLane Green Ad Network.  For example, we use services provided by third parties for the targeted and measured delivery of ads to publisher sites based on criteria selected by such publishers and the advertisers and agencies advertising on such websites.  These services use tags (web beacons, programming code or HTML that request the delivery of an ad) and technology designed to enable the capture and reporting of post-impression and/or post-click visitor activity.  Because these activities occur on publisher sites and not on our Sites, this Privacy Policy does not apply to publisher sites that participate in the SustainLane Green Ad Network.  You are encouraged to review the privacy policies applicable to publisher sites for more information about their privacy practices.

To learn more about the collection of information by the services provided by DoubleClick, including how to opt out of such collection, please visit: <http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/index.aspx>

**6.** ******Minors**

"Minors" (as defined under the laws of their jurisdiction or residence) are not eligible to register on our Sites or use or purchase the products or services available thereon. We do not knowingly collect Personally Identifiable Information from any Minor, and will not use this information if we discover that it has been provided by a Minor.

**7.** ******Linked Sites**

For your convenience there are links to web sites operated by companies other than SustainableCircles (" **Third Party Sites** ") that we believe may be of interest to you. SustainableCircles does not disclose your Personally Identifiable Information to these Third Party Sites without obtaining your consent. SustainableCircles does not endorse and is not responsible for the privacy practices of these Third Party Sites. If you choose to link to one of these Third Party Sites, you should review the privacy policy posted on this other web site to understand how that Third Party Site collects and uses your Personally Identifiable Information.

**8.** ******SustainableCircles Security Procedures**

The security and confidentiality of your information is extremely important to us. We have implemented technical, administrative, and physical security measures to protect your information from unauthorized access and improper use. From time to time, we review our security procedures in order to consider appropriate new technology and methods. Despite SustainableCircles' efforts to protect your Personally Identifiable Information, there is always some risk that an unauthorized third party may find a way around our security systems or that transmissions of your information over the Internet will be intercepted. The following are some of the security procedures that SustainableCircles uses to protect your privacy:

**(a)** **** SustainableCircles requires both a personal username and a password in order for users to access their Personally Identifiable Information.

**(b)** **** SustainableCircles uses firewalls to protect information held in our servers.

**(c)** **** SustainableCircles utilizes Secure Socket Layer (SSL) encryption in transmitting Personally Identifiable Information to our servers. In order to take advantage of encryption technology, you must have an Internet browser which supports 128-bit encryption.

**(d)** **** SustainableCircles closely monitors the limited number of SustainableCircles employees who have potential access to your Personally Identifiable Information.

**(e)** **** SustainableCircles requires all SustainableCircles employees to abide by our Privacy Policy and be subject to disciplinary action if they violate it.

**(f)** **** SustainableCircles backs-up our systems to protect the integrity of your Personally Identifiable Information.

**9.** ******Changes To This Privacy Policy**

Please note that SustainableCircles reviews its privacy practices from time to time, and that these practices are subject to change. We ask that you bookmark and periodically review this web page to ensure continuing familiarity with the most current version of our Privacy Policy. To contact SustainableCircles about privacy issues, to report a violation of our Privacy Policy, or to raise any other issue, please e-mail us at [piqngfxo2](http://www.sustainlane.com/#).

**10.** ******Deleting Your Personally Identifiable Information**

If you want to (a) delete your Personally Identifiable Information from our systems, (b) update the Personally Identifiable Information that you have provided to us, or (c) change your preferences with respect to contacts or other activities, you can email us at [ip_rti3vpazcqyj](http://www.sustainlane.com/#). We try to promptly answer every email, but may not always be able to do so. Keep in mind, however, that there will be residual information that will remain within SustainableCircles databases, access logs and other records, which may or may not contain such personally identifiable information. SustainableCircles reserves the right, from time to time, to contact former users of our Sites. 

If you do not receive adequate resolution of a privacy-related problem or if you have any privacy-related questions, you may write to SustainableCircles Privacy Help Desk at:

SustainableCircles Corporation  
Attn: Privacy Help Desk  
870 Market Street, Suite 1011  
San Francisco, California 94102  
Or call us at:  
(415) 392-5263 Ext. 10
